mibank.com 2006-03-26

# M&I Banking the way it was meant to be.™

| 

**Protecting Your Privacy**  
Privacy policies and practices at Marshall & Ilsley Corporation (M&I)

_Over 150 Years of Integrity and Service_

M&I's history began in 1847, and today, M&I ranks among the nation's oldest and largest financial institutions. For more than 150 years, our commitment to our customers has remained unchanged. We will continue to help you build financial security by providing you with expert advice and a wide range of quality products and services. We will also continue to serve you with integrity and discretion at all times.

Keeping your information confidential and secure is an important part of our responsibility to you… and we take this responsibility very seriously. This notice describes our policies and practices that protect your information. We also provide you with options about how your information may be shared within M&I and with others as required or permitted by law – including those who may work with us to better serve your needs.

_Please read on to learn more about the ways in which we are working to protect your privacy. We recognize and value the trust you have placed in us, and as always, we will continue to serve you with integrity and respect in the years to come._

**Background Note:** The privacy policies and practices described here apply to the M&I affiliates identified below. These policies may be amended at any time. We will keep you informed of any applicable changes as required by law.

Some of the terms used in this notice include the following:

  * "Affiliates" include companies related to M&I through common control or ownership. We refer to our affiliates as members of the M&I family.
  * "Customer" refers to individuals who apply for or use products and services primarily for personal, family or household purposes that are provided through the M&I affiliates listed in this notice, or have done so in the past.
  * "Nonaffiliated third parties" include third parties that are not members of our corporate family, but with whom we may have a special arrangement or joint marketing agreement.
  * "Nonpublic personal information" refers to customer information available to M&I through the collection of information described in this notice.

**1\. We apply high standards of confidentiality and security in order to safeguard your nonpublic personal information.**

Our employees access nonpublic personal information in relation to their job functions and the services they provide to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard your nonpublic personal information.

On our Web site(s), we use a full range of Internet security measures such as data encryption, Secure Socket Layer technology, and user name and passwords. Please note, however, that when you use a link from our Web site(s) to a non-M&I site, M&I privacy policies and Internet security measures no longer apply.

**2\. By collecting and maintaining accurate nonpublic personal information, we learn more about your needs and are better able to provide superior customer service to you.**

We collect and maintain nonpublic personal information in order to:

  * Protect your accounts from unauthorized access or identity theft.
  * Help ensure the security of your transactions with M&I, including online transactions.
  * Service your accounts accurately and efficiently.
  * Provide you with products and services designed to match your needs now and in the future.
  * Introduce you to special offers and opportunities available through the M&I family and others.

The nonpublic personal information we collect may include: 
  * Information we receive from you on applications or other loan and account forms, such as your name, address, assets and income.
  * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates or others, and information to verify representations made by you, such as your account balance, payment history, parties to transactions, and credit usage.
  * Information we receive from third parties, including credit bureaus, such as your creditworthiness, credit score and payment history.
  * Information we obtain regarding your employment, credit or other relationships, such as your employment history.
  * Information submitted by you for insurance applications or claims, such as medical information, that is used exclusively for the specific purposes you have authorized.

Collection of information on our Web site(s) may include data such as pages visited, downloads, other Web sites from which visitors arrive, and the types of operating systems and browsers used. We collect this information to personalize the information displayed and to enhance the performance of the site. M&I may also offer online planning tools, such as calculators, to help you evaluate your personal finances or decide whether an M&I product is right for you. Information obtained through online planning tools, or online payments and transfers, may be used in connection with the transaction you initiate.

**3\. Information sharing is limited.**

From time to time, there may be products and services, from either within or outside the M&I family, that we think may be of interest to you. To offer such products and services to you, we may need to share your nonpublic personal information with M&I affiliates or with nonaffiliated third parties.

**Information sharing with affiliates:** In our efforts to better serve your financial needs, we may share the nonpublic personal information we collect as described above with M&I affiliates. We want to be sure we understand your entire relationship with us when addressing your needs, providing you services, developing products and determining what products you may want to know about.

You may ask us not to share certain information with M&I affiliates including:

  * Information we obtain from your application, such as your income, assets, or employer.
  * Information we obtain from a consumer report, such as your credit score or credit history.
  * Information we obtain to verify representations made by you, such as your creditors or assets.
  * Information we obtain from another person regarding your employment, credit or other relationships, such as your employment history.

You have a choice as to whether or not you want this information shared among our affiliates. If you prefer that we not share this information within the M&I family, you may opt out. However, even if you have opted out, we may still share this information with certain M&I affiliates that perform technical or operational support services. These services include approving applications, preparing documents and account statements, and servicing your accounts. We also share information with M&I affiliates, where permitted by law, about your transactions and experiences with us (such as your account balances and transaction history), even if you have opted out.

**Information sharing with nonaffiliated third parties:** We may share nonpublic personal information we collect as described above with nonaffiliated third parties, such as:

  * Third parties that provide services necessary to effect, administer or enforce a transaction that you request or authorize.
  * Credit bureaus or similar reporting agencies.
  * Law enforcement officers and governmental agencies and courts as required by a subpoena, court order or law.
  * Third parties that perform marketing or other services on our behalf.
  * Other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements.
  * Others to the extent permitted or required by law.

We may share your nonpublic personal information with the types of nonaffiliated third parties described directly above, even if you have opted out.

In order to provide products and services that we think may be of interest to you, we may also share your nonpublic personal information with nonfinancial companies (such as retailers) and financial service providers (such as insurance agents). If you prefer that we not share your nonpublic personal information with them, you may opt out.

**Information sharing in private-label credit card and affinity programs:** You may receive M&I products or services, such as an M&I credit card, through a private-label credit card or affinity program sponsored by a nonaffiliated third party. As part of your participation in the program, the program sponsor may offer benefits to you, such as products or services offered by retail merchants as well as other M&I services. We may share nonpublic personal information collected as a result of your participation in a private-label credit card or affinity program with the program sponsor to assist the sponsor in making offers of other products or services to you, where permitted by law.

 **4\. You have a choice about information sharing.**

If you prefer that we not share your nonpublic personal information (except in those circumstances, described above, that are permitted or required by law), you may opt out at any time by notifying us not to share with M&I affiliates as well as nonaffiliated third parties. To notify us, call our toll-free automated service at **1-888-450-3185**. You will be requested to provide identifying customer information at that time, including your Social Security number.

By opting out, you will be excluded from receiving some information about benefits or offers from either within or outside the M&I family, for which you may be eligible.

For accounts that are held jointly by more than one customer, any of the account holders may opt out on behalf of the other account holders. Any opt out instructions received from one owner of a joint account will apply also to individual accounts in that person's name as well as any other accounts held jointly by that person, based on the data available to M&I.

If you participate in a private-label credit card program or other affinity program offering M&I products or services, please review the privacy policy (if any) of your program's sponsor for additional information about your opt-out rights as their customer.

**  
5\. Additional information to help you.**

**Furnishing Negative Information.** _We may report information about your account to credit bureaus. Late payments, missed payments, or other defaults on your account may be reflected in your credit report._

**Access to accounts.** If you believe someone has accessed your accounts without authorization, or if someone has discovered your personal identification number (PIN), Personal Security Code, user name or password ("Codes"), please notify us at 1-888-464-5463 as soon as possible. Please assist us in this effort by protecting your Codes and account numbers. These numbers are for your personal use and should be kept confidential by you. Our employees and associates will never contact you for your Codes or other personal identification numbers.

**Accuracy of customer information.** _We are committed to keeping your nonpublic personal information accurate. If you believe our records are outdated or incorrect, please contact M &I at M&I Direct, P.O. Box 622, Milwaukee, WI, 53201-0622. We will investigate the situation and make any necessary updates as soon as possible._

**Web site(s).** The information you request from our Web site(s) about your accounts can only be accessed with your Codes. It is your responsibility to keep your Codes confidential. Messages you send to us by e-mail are subject to viewing, alteration, and copying by potentially anyone on the Internet. We encourage you to send confidential correspondence through either the Postal Service or by using the telephone to speak directly to our employees.

**Credit bureaus.** If you would like to have your name removed from prescreened credit mailing lists obtained from the main consumer credit reporting agencies – TransUnion, Experian, Equifax, and Innovis – call 1-888-5OPTOUT (888-567-8688).

**This notice applies to the following M &I affiliates:**

| M&I Marshall & Ilsley Bank | M&I Dealer Finance, Inc.  
---|---  
M&I Bank FSB | M&I Brokerage Services, Inc.  
Southwest Bank of St. Louis | Marshall & Ilsley Trust Company N.A.  
M&I Insurance Company of Arizona, Inc. | M&I Investment Management Corp.  
M&I Mortgage Corp. | M&I Insurance Services, Inc.  
  
Other M&I affiliates, such as Metavante Corporation, may have their own privacy policies.  
Rev. 12/2005
